Guide to the Bob Gore Photographs 2017, 2020 PR 424
New-York Historical Society
Bob Gore photographs
2017, 2020
New-York Historical Society
Gore, Bob (photographer)
PR 424
1.5 Linear feet in two flat file folders
The collection includes 11 16x20 inch, color photographic prints from Bob Gore's series of images of Brooklyn's West Indian American Parade (2017) and of the social justice protests in New York in response to the killing of George Floyd (2020).
Biographical / Historical
Bob Gore (Robert Gore, Jr.) is a professional photographer, active since the 1980s, who is known for his photographs documenting worship traditions throughout the U.S. and the Caribbean. Gore has also worked extensively in television broadcasting. He is President of Bob Gore Productions, a television production company, which broadcasts the weekly program from Jamaica and Trinidad, 'Caribbean International Network' in New York City. Prior to forming BGP, Gore held management positions with Group W Television (now CBS) in New York; WGBH-TV/FM in Boston; and WNYC-TV, where he held the position of station manager, and instituted the first daily offering of primetime Black programming on American broadcast television.
Gore has a long history of civic engagement. He is a longtime member of Harlem's Abyssinian Baptist Church and serves as the church's official photographer. In 1984 he was New York State Campaign Manager for the Jesse Jackson for President Campaign. During the peak of the Chicago Freedom Movement, he served as treasurer of Chicago C.O.R.E. (Congress of Racial Equality); was a field staff volunteer with SCLC (Southern Christian Leadership Conference) headed by the Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr; and a field manager for VISTA (Volunteers in Service To America).
Since 2006 he has been an advisor to Bethlehem Ministry, a non-sectarian organization supporting a school, a clinic and economic development programs in northeast Haiti. Bob Gore is the author of two books: "We've come this far: the Abyssinian Baptist Church: a photographic journal" (2001); and "Good news from Haiti: the work of Bethlehem Ministry" (2009).
(The above note was taken with minor changes from the biographical note for Bob Gore found on Brooklyn Public Library's webpage for their collection of Gore's photographs.)
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The West Indian American Parade photographs were purchased from the photographer, 2018. The George Floyd protest photographs were acquired from the photographer in March 2021. Of these, one photograph (#26. George Floyd) was purchased from Bob Gore, through the generosity of Helen and Robert Appel. The other four photographs were a gift from Gore.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes eleven 16x20 inch, color photographic prints taken by photographer Bob Gore. These include five photographs from his series of images of Brooklyn's West Indian American Parade (2017) and six photographs of the social justice protests in New York in response to the killing of George Floyd (2020). The titles within the series as provided by Gore are listed below, with additional description of the image added at points by the processing archivist.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by photograph series as defined by Bob Gore.
Color photographs.; Black lives matter movement -- New York State -- New York.; Civil rights demonstrations -- New York State -- New York.; Floyd, George, 1973-2020; West Indian American Day Carnival Parade (Brooklyn, N.Y.) [111]
- Series I. West Indian American Parade, 2017 September 4
  - 1. African American man with white beard and black hat and vest, 2017 (Folder FF-1)
  - 2. Lucifer in White costume, 2017 (Folder FF-1)
  - 3. Close up of woman with blue makeup highlights, 2017 (Folder FF-1)
  - 4. Woman in massive red and yellow feather ensemble, 2017 (Folder FF-1)
  - 5. Woman in multicolored costume with winglike structures, 2017 (Folder FF-1)
- Series II. George Floyd Protests New York, 2020
  - #6 - the police behind the barricades, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
  - #7 - prayers, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
    Scope and Contents
    Group in prostrate posture for prayer.
  - #8 - the army vet, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
    Self-proclaimed Army veteran with protest sign, with other demonstrators.
  - #13 - too many names, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
    Protester with sign declaring "Too many names" with (some) names of those killed (e.g., Breonna Taylor, Sean Bell, Tamir Rice, Sandra Bland).
  - #24 - Black Lives Matter in the window, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
    Woman displaying Black Lives Matter sign while watching from window.
  - #26 - George Floyd, 2020 (Folder FF-2)
    Protesters with poster with image of George Floyd.